<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="providers_screen_help">
        <item>Understanding Providers</item>
        <item>
            <![CDATA[
            ## Table of Contents\n\n

            - What is a provider?\n
            - Provider structure\n
            - So… where do I get providers?\n\n

            Technical questions:\n
            - How to configure a provider?\n
            - How to troubleshoot a broken provider?\n\n

            Other questions:\n
            - Is it required to install providers?\n
            - Is there a security drawback for installing a provider?\n
            - Why implement the provider system? It is confusing\n
            - Other apps have better extension system. Why should I use this?\n
            ---\n\n

            ### What is a provider?\n\n

            > The app acts as the browser while a provider acts as a browser extension\n\n
            
            How do you use your desktop browsers? Do you have AdBlocks on it? If so, providers are the _same_.\n\n
            
            To keep it simple and short, a **provider** is an optional extension of the app\'s vanilla capabilities to provide you with what content you best prefer.\n\n

            ### Provider structure\n\n

            ![Provider\'s pictograph](https://i.imgur.com/Ll6grYS.png)\n\n

            1. **Provider information (summarized)**\n
                \t- Logo of the provider\n
                \t- Name of the provider\n
                \t- Author/s of the providers\n
                \t- Content provided\n
            2. **Version of the provider**\n
                \t- The provider system recommends using [semantic versioning (semver)](https://semver.org/) for the versions of the providers.\n
            3. **Provider toggle**\n
                \t- In the app, you are allowed to disable/enable providers.\n
                \t- Disabling providers means that the app will not use it for content generation.\n
                \t- For instance, if a provider contains catalogs and it is disabled, it will not be rendered on the home and search screens.\n
            4. **Provider\'s settings**\n
                \t- Providers have their own settings which means that they are dynamically configurable based on user and author preferences.\n
                \t- If a provider asks for a configuration, then check its provider settings.\n
            5. **Provider\'s status**\n
                \t- Providers will tell you if they are working or not. The list of available statuses are:\n
                    \t\t- 🟢 _Working_\n
                    \t\t- 🔴 _Down_\n
                    \t\t- 🟡 _Maintenance_\n
                    \t\t- 🔵 _Beta_\n
            6. **Drag icon**\n
                \t- The app lets you organize and order which provider will be called up first when generating content.\n
                \t- To organize providers, press and hold a provider card then drag it to the desired order.\n

            ### So… where do I get providers?\n\n
            
            Providers are made by other developers/programmers and, currently, _GitHub repositories_ are the main source of these providers. Similar sites like GitLab and Codeberg are not yet fully supported.\n\n

            ---\n\n

            # Technical questions\n\n

            ### How to configure a provider?\n\n

            When a provider asks for a configuration, follow the instructions it will provide you with.\n\n

            Usually its configurations are included inside its provider settings which can be opened by clicking the settings button on its provider card or provider detailed information screen.\n
            ![Provider\'s settings button](https://i.imgur.com/s7H7HZD.png)\n\n

            ### How to troubleshoot a broken provider?\n\n

            Unfortunately, issues that pertains to providers must be reported to the author/s of the provider, not to the app\'s repository itself.\n\n

            However, the app recommends the following steps for you to be able to help and debug the provider:\n
            1. Test the provider.\n
                \t- Click the provider card of the provider you want to test. There should be a button to test the provider.\n
                \t![Test provider button preview](https://i.imgur.com/8SjVNWy.png)\n
            2. Get the error logs of the test.\n
                \t- You can either open and copy the log or hold-press a test case item to copy it instantly.\n
                \t![Test case item preview](https://i.imgur.com/xrL6MAu.png)\n
            3. Report the logs.\n
                \t- Click the provider card to open the provider\'s detailed information screen.\n
                \t- On the bottom of the authors section, click the _\'Issue a bug\'_ button.\n
                \t![Issue a bug button preview](https://i.imgur.com/sjRuK7T.png)\n
                \t- Paste the logs and report it.\n\n

            ---\n\n

            # Other questions\n\n

            ### Is it required to install providers?\n\n
            
            No. Like many browser extensions, they are purely optional to install, but you are free to do so.\n\n

            ### Is there a security drawback for installing a provider?\n\n

            Yes. Each provider accessible through the app is not securely monitored by the author(s) of the app.\n\n

            When you install a provider, _it can access the whole context of the app_ such as device storage, notifications, etc. which is considerably a common security flaw for android apps.\n\n

            Installing a provider is entirely up to your judgment, with all risks and responsibilities falling on you. Trust or not to trust? It\'s up to you!\n\n
            
            ### Why implement the provider system? It is confusing.\n\n

            It is to tailor the experiences and customize the user preferences. This way, we can also increase user engagement and have more people use the app.\n\n

            It also prioritizes building a developer-friendly community. Nerds 🤓 and non-nerds can create a community based on their similar interests and needs that are related to the app.\n\n

            Lastly, it is to separate the responsibilities of the providers from the app. Issues related to providers are incredibly hard to maintain.\n\n

            ### Other apps have better _extension_ system. Why should I use this?\n\n

            Yes, definitely! Use those apps instead for a better user experience. The app is still in its early stages, and we can not expect major updates in immediate time.\n
            ]]>
        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>